Diego Thon Cortés

Front-End Developer

CONTACT

+ (56) 9 84137867 diegothoncortes@gmail.com

SKILLS

CSS (scss - less)
Bootstrap
Tailwind (Beginner)
Angular Material
JavaScript
Angular
ReactJS (Beginner)
Firebase
Git

NodeJS (Beginner)

Spanish (Native)
English (C1 Advanced)

CERTIFICATIONS

EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

ABOUT ME

Web developer, with 2 years and 9 months of experience in programming languages, tools and frameworks, mainly performing the role of Semi-senior programmer.

My IT background includes Front-end development on web platforms.

All this making use of agile methodologies when addressing projects, particularly with Scrum methodology.

Within my skills I highlight pro-activity, self-taught, and desire to learn new things within the field of IT and web development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer (Soho)

6/2022 - Current

- Redesign of graphic interface for web platform proposed by the User (Gasco, Zurich, Itau Bank).
- Usage of external API's to create online payment using providers such as Webpay and Zumpago.
- Keeping clean and documented code with low quantity of bugs in case of future changes and improvements.
- Used Flexbox and @Media only screen for responsiveness and adaptability before different viewports.
- Framework used: Angular 11+.
- Management of Jira and Kanban board for the tasks states and Confluence for documentation.
- Used Bitbucket for repositories.

Front-End Developer (Everis NTT DATA)

1/2021 - 6/2022

- Update and re-design of graphic interface on applications proposed by the user (LATAM Airlines Alemana Clinic).
- Updating and creating new services and Http queries for the usage of APIs.
- Keep clean and updated code for future changes.
- Using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap for various projects.
- Creation of the full DispoOnline Front-end Latam Project.
- Framework: Angular 8+.
- Management of Jira Kanban board for the detail of tasks.
- Management of BitBucket and GitLab repositories.

Front-End Developer (Municipal Corporation)

5/2019 - 12/2019

- Making of Web Application, focused in the sale of graveyard lands in Pozo Almonte.
- Programming language used for Front-end Angular 7.

EDUCATION

Inacap Valdivia, Chile (University)

- Computer engineering, 2012 - 2018

2019 - Graduated

2019 - Licensed